yeah what do you do when you need
progesterone but cannot tolerate it I've
taken the oral vaginal and rectal these
increase my anxiety make me puke and
cause horrible dizziness my levels are
so
low yeah so this is this is a tough one
and and I I go through this with some of
my patients so for the most part
progesterone is very well tolerated and
people love it but every now and then
there is somebody who really just does
not tolerate progesterone and so so
normally yes normally it keeps us calm
helps us sleep but sometimes it can make
make people more anxious and it can make
people bloated and I that's the the big
thing that I see is that women and again
it's it's fairly rare but it's common
enough to where I do see it here and
there women will complain of getting
bloated of of feeling too Moody and so
you do need some progesterone to balance
the estrogen but you don't really need
that much so I will try to give just a
very little bit of progesterone like
maybe 25 milligrams we use sublingual
tabs so
commercially commercially you can only
give what exists right and this is a
problem with commercial drugs like
because you can only you can only give
what there is and like right so with
progesterone commercially at least in in
America so we have 100 and we have 200
and that's it and they're capsules so
you can't break them so you are just
basically stuck with that so we use
compounded products and what's great
about the compounded products is you can
you can make whatever you want so for
the ladies that really don't tolerate
progesterone I'll do something like like
25 milligrams of progesterone like 10
days out of the month and a really low
dose like that seems to be all you need
to really to balance out the estrogen to
because to give unopposed estrogen you
know you can have too much proliferation
of the uterine lining and so you need
some progesterone to balance it but just
giving a little bit generally generally
works pretty well and you can always you
know you can always work to see what if
you get the dose low enough it will be
tolerated okay so yeah and then and then
you just have to find another way to
work on the Sleep um because that's a
big thing as as us ladies get older we
stop sleeping it's one of Nature's ways
of taking us out and uh I've experienced
that myself I always slept really well
until I was in my I think 44 all of a
sudden I stopped sleeping would sweat at
night now I take my progesterone I sleep
I'm dry um but if you if you don't
tolerate the progesterone you know um
melatonin herbal supplements cannabis
magnesium um but but you you will be
able to tolerate the progesterone if you
give a low enough dose yeah great
tips